- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
kids:
Aye, aye, Captain!
孩子们：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
kids:
Aye, aye, Captain!
孩子们：
是啊是啊，队长！
- ♪ Ohh... ♪
- ♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
kids:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
孩子们：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
- ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
kids:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
孩子们：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
- ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
kids:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
孩子们：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
- ♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
kids: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
孩子们：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
♪ ♪
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
♪ ♪
- End of another
18-hour shift of misery.
- 另一个的结束
18小时轮班的痛苦。
- Ooh! Ahoy there!
- 哦！哎哟！
And what do you two laddies
have planned for this weekend?
你们两个女士怎么办？
这个周末有计划吗？
- I'm polishing Gary's shell.
- 我正在擦亮加里的外壳。
[whirring]
[呼呼]
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
[growls]
[咆哮]
Well, I'm going
to a post-post-pre-modern
嗯，我这就去
到后后前现代
unconstructivist
dance performance.
非建构主义
舞蹈表演。
[futuristic music]
[未来派音乐]
- Uh, well, that's fascinating.
- 呃，这很有趣。
♪ ♪
Hey, instead of that malarkey,
嘿，不是那个胡说八道的人，
what would you say
to a leisurely weekend
你会说什么
到一个悠闲的周末
sailing trip
on me brand-new yacht?
航海之旅
在我全新的游艇上？
Huh?
[chuckles]
啊？
[笑声]
The sun in your face. Huh?
阳光照在你的脸上。啊？
- Ooh.
- 哦。
[laughs laboriously]
[吃力地笑]
- The wind in your--
- 你的风--
uh, head wrinkles.
嗯，头上有皱纹。
- [sighs] Hmm.
- [叹气] 嗯。
Well, I wouldn't mind a nice,
relaxing ocean cruise.
嗯，我不介意一个好的，
轻松的海洋巡游。
- Great.
- 伟大的。
I'll see you at the dock
我会在码头见你
bright and early
tomorrow morning.
又亮又早
明天早上。
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
- [sighs]
Mm-hmm.
- [叹气]
嗯嗯。
- Mr. Krabs, I'm all dressed up
and ready to...
- 螃蟹先生，我已经盛装打扮了
并准备...
snorkel.
通气管。
- Wait a second.
- 等一下。
- Uh, Mr. Krabs,
where's your ship?
- 呃，蟹老板先生，
你的船在哪里？
- Something smells fishy.
- 有股鱼腥味。
- Don't get your mizzenmast
in a twist.
- 不要抓住你的后桅
在一个转折中。
I got your ship right here.
我已经把你的船放在这里了。
[both grunt]
[两人咕哝]
[chuckles]
Some assembly required.
[笑声]
需要一些组装。
- We have to build the ship?
- 我们必须建造这艘船？
- Yay!
We get to build the ship!
- 耶！
我们要建造这艘船！
- Premade vessels
are for landlubbers.
- 预制容器
是给旱鸭子的。
Real sailors
build their own ships.
真正的水手
建造自己的船只。
Now get to work, you two.
现在开始工作吧，你们两个。
And as an old Navy man,
作为一名老海军，
I'll be responsible
for the most difficult part.
我会负责
对于最困难的部分。
- And that would be?
- 那会是吗？
- Supervising.
- 监督。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[snoring]
[打鼾]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
Old Navy man?
老海军？
Ha! More like old, lazy man.
哈!更像是又老又懒的人。
Hmm.
唔。
[sighs]
Oh, boy.
[叹气]
哦，男孩。
All right,
let's get this over with.
好吧，
让我们结束这件事吧。
Now, where are
the instructions?
现在，在哪里
说明？
- I'll find them.
- [grunting
- 我会找到他们的。
- [咕哝
- Instructions, instructions...
- 指示，指示……
How to assemble...
- [yelps]
如何组装...
- [尖叫声]
- Got them!
- 找到他们了！
Hmm, step one.
嗯，第一步。
- [moans]
- [呻吟]
Give me that.
给我那个。
Hmm--huh?
[wind blows]
嗯——嗯？
[风吹过]
[groans]
[呻吟]
[propeller whirs]
[螺旋桨呼呼地响]
Now, what are we
supposed to do?
现在，我们是什么
应该做什么？
- Don't worry, Squidward,
- 别担心，章鱼哥
I know exactly
how to handle this situation.
我确切地知道
如何处理这种情况。
- Oh, really?
- 哦真的吗？
- We just need
to follow our hearts.
- 我们只需要
跟随我们的心。
♪ La, la, la ♪
♪ 啦啦啦 ♪
- Oh.
- 哦。
[quirky music]
[古怪的音乐]
[groans]
Hmm...
[呻吟]
嗯...
- Squidward,
I did the first piece.
- 章鱼哥，
我做了第一件作品。
- SpongeBob, you clam-head,
- 海绵宝宝，你这个呆头呆脑的人，
you don't put up
the mast first.
你不忍受
首先是桅杆。
- [shouting]
What's that, Squidward?
- [喊叫]
那是什么，章鱼哥？
- I said,
"SpongeBob, you clam-head"--
- 我说，
“海绵宝宝，你这个蛤蟆头”——
[groans]
[呻吟]
[moans]
[呻吟声]
- Hey!
- 嘿！
- You have to start
with the frame.
- 你必须开始
与框架。
All right,
now bend it into a boat shape.
好吧，
现在将其弯曲成船形。
D'oh!
噢！
♪ ♪
[yelps]
[尖叫声]
[whistles and clangs]
[口哨声和叮当声]
- Tickle, tickle, tickle.
- 挠痒痒，挠痒痒，挠痒痒。
- SpongeBob,
wood planks are not--
- 海绵宝宝，
木板不是——
- [laughs]
- [笑]
- Ticklish.
- 怕痒。
[yelps]
[尖叫声]
[screams]
[whistles and clangs]
[口哨声和叮当声]
- We did it, Squidward.
Put her there.
- 我们做到了，章鱼哥。
把她放在那里。
- [weakly]
Hooray.
- [微弱]
万岁。
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
Whoa! Ha!
哇！哈!
Ooh! Hey! Aah!
哦！嘿！啊啊！
Aah! Ooh! Hey! Aah!
啊啊！哦！嘿！啊啊！
Uh-oh!
呃-哦！
[yelps]
[尖叫声]
- [gasps] Huh?
- [喘气] 啊？
[growls]
[咆哮]
What in the name of all
that's salty are you doing?
以所有人的名义
你做的那个很咸吗？
You're wasting
expensive lumber-er-er-er.
你在浪费
- We're trying to build
the ship's frame, Mr. Krabs.
- 我们正在努力构建
船体，蟹老板。
- Pfft.
- 噗。
Building the frame?
构建框架？
They give you one
all ready to go.
他们给你一个
一切准备就绪。
- Ooh!
- 哦！
- Take a gander, boy-o.
- 看一看，男孩。
- Ooh--
- 噢--
[gags]
[笑点]
I'm shipshape, Mr. Krabs.
我很健康，蟹老板。
- Now get back to work.
The tide's going out.
- 现在回去工作吧。
潮水要退了。
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
- [sighs]
- [叹气]
[orchestral music]
[管弦乐]
♪ ♪
- Oh, a stubborn one, eh?
- 哦，一个固执的人，是吗？
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
[sighs]
Mm-hmm.
[叹气]
嗯嗯。
♪ ♪
- Hmm...
- 唔...
[strains]
[菌株]
- Hmm? Huh?
- 唔？啊？
[yelps]
[尖叫声]
- [panting]
- [气喘吁吁]
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
Huh--whoa!
哈——哇！
♪ ♪
[groans]
[呻吟]
[growls]
[咆哮]
♪ ♪
Huh?
[strains]
啊？
[菌株]
♪ ♪
[moans]
- Squidward!
[呻吟声]
- 章鱼哥！
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
- Did you see an anchor?
- 你看到锚了吗？
I think I dropped one.
我想我掉了一个。
- Why don't we switch places?
- 我们为什么不换个地方呢？
You work down here
and I'll work up there.
你在这里工作
我会在那里工作。
[sighs]
Much safer.
[叹气]
安全得多。
Never work below an idiot.
永远不要在白痴之下工作。
- Oops!
Look out above!
- 哎呀！
往上看！
- Above?
- 多于？
[grunts]
[咕哝]
That's it!
就是这样！
♪ ♪
- Huh--whoa!
- 哈--哇！
Oh, hi, Squidward.
- [growls]
哦，嗨，章鱼哥。
- [咆哮]
- Have you seen a safe up here?
I think I dropped it.
- 你看到这里有保险箱吗？
我想我把它扔掉了。
- [yelps]
- [尖叫声]
[growls]
[咆哮]
From now on,
you're working next to me
从现在开始，
你在我旁边工作
where I can keep an eye on you.
我可以在哪里监视你。
- Aw, that's so sweet,
Squidward.
- 噢，太甜蜜了，
章鱼哥。
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
[explosion]
[爆炸]
- Wow.
- 哇。
Mr. Krabs,
your ship is finished!
蟹老板先生，
你的船已经完成了！
- We use the term "ship"
very loosely.
- 我们使用“船”一词
非常宽松。
[gull cries]
[海鸥的叫声]
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
[foghorn blows]
[雾号吹响]
Hmm,
she's a little off the beam.
嗯，
她有点偏离正轨了。
Hmm...
唔...
Hmm, I know!
嗯，我知道！
All she needs is a nice,
shiny coat of paint.
她所需要的只是一个美好的，
闪亮的油漆层。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
♪ ♪
The S.S. Sea-cret Formula
is ready to set sail...
S.S. Sea-cret 配方
已准备好起航……
as soon as you two drag her
into the lagoon.
只要你们两个拖着她
进入泻湖。
[both strain]
[两种菌株]
- Mush!
- 糊涂！
♪ ♪
both: Huh?
两人：啊？
♪ ♪
[bell dings]
[铃声]
- [hums]
- [哼哼]
- [gasping]
- [喘气]
Well, at least this weekend
isn't a total waste.
好吧，至少这个周末
并不是完全浪费。
- Not so fast, Mr. Squidward.
- 没那么快，章鱼哥先生。
You still have work to do.
你还有工作要做。
- Huh? Work?
- 啊？工作？
♪ ♪
[bell dings]
[铃声]
- Welcome to the grand opening
- 欢迎来到盛大开幕
of the Krusty Krab
of the high seas...
蟹堡王的
公海的...
and even higher prices.
甚至更高的价格。
[laughs]
[笑]
- Huh! Forget it!
- 哈！忘了它！
I am not moving from this spot.
我不会离开这个地方。
- No problem.
- 没问题。
- Huh?
- 啊？
♪ ♪
- How exciting, Squidward!
- 多么令人兴奋啊，章鱼哥！
I get to flip patties and be--
我要翻转馅饼然后——
[gags]
Seasick at the same time.
[笑点]
同时晕船。
[retches]
[干呕]
- We're not gonna sell any food
in the middle of a lagoon!
- 我们不会出售任何食物
在泻湖中央！
- I'd like one Krabby Patty
combo with extra combo on it.
- 我想要一份蟹肉饼
组合上有额外的组合。
[ka-ching]
[嘉庆]
- [panting]
- [气喘吁吁]
[bell dings]
[铃声]
[gags, retches]
[作呕，干呕]
- Your order.
- 你的订单。
- At ease, sailor.
- 放心，水手。
[slurps drink]
- [sighs]
[喝水]
- [叹气]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
[screams]
[尖叫声]
♪ ♪
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
- [chuckles]
- [轻笑]
[whistle blows]
[哨声响起]
Whee!
哎哟！
♪ ♪
Yeah!
[laughs]
是的！
[笑]
Whoo!
呼！
both: Mmm!
两人：嗯！
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
[cheering]
[欢呼]
♪ ♪
- Whoa!
- 哇！
[ka-ching]
[嘉庆]
- Huh? Hmm...
- 啊？唔...
I didn't know there was
an island in Goo Lagoon.
我不知道有
古泻湖中的一个岛屿。
[tense music]
[紧张的音乐]
- [laughs]
- Huh?
- [笑]
- 啊？
Butt-berg, dead ahead!
巴特伯格，就在前方！
- [gasps] Huh?
- [喘气] 啊？
Everyone, hold fast!
- Whoa!
大家一定要坚持住！
- 哇！
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[screams]
[bell rings]
[尖叫声]
[铃声响起]
[horn blows]
[号角吹响]
- Great Neptune's nose hair!
- 伟大的海王星的鼻毛！
- [screams, grunts]
- [尖叫声、咕哝声]
[bell rings]
[铃声响起]
- [yelps]
- [尖叫声]
- [whimpers]
- [呜咽]
[scraping]
[刮]
Hmm?
唔？
[strains]
[菌株]
Hmm...
唔...
♪ ♪
[Squidward playing "Taps"]
[章鱼哥演奏“Taps”]
- One double Krabby Patty,
please.
- 一张双人蟹肉饼，
请。
[ka-ching]
[嘉庆]
♪ ♪
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
[eerie music]
[诡异的音乐]
♪ ♪
- [roars]
- [咆哮]
Give me all the Krabby Patties
you got, kid.
把所有的蟹黄饼都给我
你有，孩子。
Oh, I'm so hungry,
哦，我好饿，
I could eat at the Chum Bucket
and like it.
我可以在 Chum Bucket 吃饭
并喜欢它。
Boy, I'll tell you--
[retches]
孩子，我告诉你——
[干呕]
- [sighs]
Oh, boy.
- [叹气]
哦，男孩。